[Strawberry milk is Gin's favorite. Get lots of calcium and your bones will be strong]
[The client is an old man on his last legs.  He's literally "dead or alive."]
["Look, Overly Sticky Sweet Dumplings Are Not Real Dumplings, You Idiot!"]
あぁん？ ちょっとぐらい
違っててもいいんだよ！
What? So what if it's a little different?!
みんな違って みんないいって
言葉を知らねえのか!?
Don't you know the saying "Everyone's different, and everyone's great?"
ﾅﾝﾊﾞｰ１より ｵﾝﾘｰ１だろ！
It's not Number One, it's the Only One!
いらついてんじゃねえよ！
Quit complaining!
むかつくとか言っときゃ➡
You're badly mistaken if you think you can get by in this world by blaming everyone else.
世間を渡れると思ったら
大間違いだ！
世の中 鬼だらけなんだよ！
The world is full of demons!
Now listen up! This is what's important!
いいか！ 大事なのは これだ～!!
[Calcium]
Yes, calcium!
そうだ！ ｶﾙｼｳﾑだ!!
As long as you get plenty of calcium, everything will turn out fine.
ｶﾙｼｳﾑさえ摂っときゃ
すべて うまくいくんだよ！
Cramming for exams? Fights with your parents?
受験戦争｡ 親との確執｡
気になる あの娘｡ 股間のにおい｡
That girl you like? A smelly crotch?
とりあえず ｶﾙｼｳﾑ摂っときゃ
すべて うまくいく！
Get your calcium and it'll all work out
No, it won't!
いくわけねえだろ!!
いくら ｶﾙｼｳﾑ摂ったってなぁ➡
No matter how much calcium you drink, if you get hit by a car, your leg's still gonna break!
車にはねられりゃ 骨も折れるわ！
I got hit too, but I'm fine!
ｵﾚも はねられたけど
ﾋﾟﾝﾋﾟﾝしてんじゃねえか｡
毎日 ｺｲﾂ 飲んでるおかげだよ｡
It's all because I drink this every day.
いちご牛乳しか飲めないくせに
偉そうなんだよ！
Don't act so high and mighty. You just like the taste of strawberry milk!
んだ～ ｺﾗ～！
ｺｰﾋｰ牛乳も飲めるぞ～!!
What?! I drink coffee milk too, you know!
(神楽)１日800ｷﾛｶﾛﾘｰ
塩分 控えめ｡
800 calories every day, go easy on the salt,
pretty tasty for 300 yen per meal.
予算 １食300円のわりには
おいしいｱﾙね｡
それ ﾎﾞｸの病院食！
That's my hospital meal!
いちご牛乳 飲んどけ｡
いちご牛乳｡
Just drink strawberry milk, strawberry milk.
うわっ くさっ！ 息 甘っ！
Your breath! Sickly sweet!
なんだと～!?
銀さんは 甘い息を吐いた｡
What? Gin exhales his "sweet breath".
ぐわ～っ！ 新八は
99ﾎﾟｲﾝﾄのﾀﾞﾒｰｼﾞを受けた!!
Argh! Shinpachi sustains 99 points of damage!
(婦長)やかましいわ～!!
(銀時/新八)んっ!?
Keep the noise down!
You're bothering the other patients!
他の患者さんの迷惑なんだよ！
今 まさに➡
There's even one who's on the verge of death. Do you get me, you little creep?!
ﾃﾞｯﾄﾞ ｵｱ ｱﾗｲﾌﾞをさまよう
患者さんだっているんだよ ﾎﾞｹが!!
すみません…
ｺｲﾂが うるさくて…｡
Oh, sorry. He's so noisy.
ｱﾝﾀ ﾎﾝﾄに 人間 腐ってるな！
(２人)ふごっ！
You're a really awful person!
(ｱﾅｳﾝｽ)じゃいじぇん教授の
総回診です｡
It is time for Professor Jaijien to make his rounds.
♪♪～
Look, I'm a grown man, so just leave me alone.
もう いい大人なんですから
いいかげんにしてくださいよ｡
ﾎﾞｸが 病院に
いづらくなっちゃうんですから｡
You're making it hard for me to stay in the hospital.
人間 いくつになっても
居場所探しの 旅の途中だろ｡
No matter how old we get, we are all on a journey in search of our place in life.
ﾌｫｰｸｿﾝｸﾞ風に
まとめてんじゃねえよ!!
Quit paraphrasing life like it's a folk song!
♪♪｢父YO 母YO ﾍｲﾍｲHO｣
Father-yo! Mother-yo! Hey-hey-ho!
♪♪｢ﾏｲﾎｰﾑ探して ﾏﾝﾎｰﾙ｣
Looking-for-my-home, in-a-manhole.
♪♪｢果てしない旅 ちかれたび｣
A long journey, a tiring one.
ﾗｯﾌﾟでも ﾀﾞﾒだから！
なに その ﾒﾛﾒﾛなﾘﾘｯｸ!!
And forget the rap music! Besides, what kind of lyrics are those?!
やれやれ｡ ｱｰﾃｨｽﾄ気取りのﾔﾂが
多すぎるな｡
Man, too many artist wannabes.
ふごっ!!
これも ｶﾙｼｳﾑ不足のせいかね…｡
I chalk it up to calcium deficiency.
≪(じじい)いちご牛乳か…｡
Strawberry milk, huh?
I drank a lot of it when I was young.
(じじい)ﾜｼも 若い頃は
飲み明かしたもんよ｡
ｷﾞｬﾙを 引き連れてなぁ…｡
With the gals in tow.
How dare you?!
(看護師)なにすんのよ～!!
おごっ…!!
さつきちゃん
ありゃ ええ子じゃった…｡
Satsuki, now she was a good girl.
そんなに いちご牛乳 飲んじゃ
体に触りますよ｡
"So much strawberry milk isn't good for you.
Drink coffee milk once in a while," is what she'd say.
たまには ｺｰﾋｰ牛乳にしたら？
なんてな｡
(じじい)ﾕｶﾘちゃん…
彼女も ぶっきらぼうだが➡
And Yukari... She was totally in-your-face. But she worried about me, too.
ﾜｼのことを 心配してくれてのう｡
It's been a long time since I've seen a "Strawberry Milky" like you!
久しぶりに 見たぞい！
いちごぎゅうにゃーをな!!
いちごぎゅうにゃー!?
Strawberry Milky?
Right.
そう！ 己の名誉にかけて
いちご牛乳を飲み続ける男を➡
A man who puts his honor on the line
and keeps drinking strawberry milk is known to all as Strawberry Milky!
人は皆
いちごぎゅうにゃーと呼ぶ!!
いや～ ｵﾚは
しがない 町の万事屋さんです｡
Nah, I'm just the Odd Jobs guy in this poor little town.
万事屋？
Odd Jobs?
And we'd better get going. We've got work to do.
そろそろ行かねえと…｡
仕事あるし｡
万事屋～!?
Odd Jobs?
Man, we're so busy. After all, I do take odd jobs.
あ～ 忙しい忙しい｡
なんたって 万事屋だからな…｡
Odd Jobs!
万事屋～!!
♪♪～
やばいｱﾙ～！ なんか
心の非常ﾍﾞﾙを押しちゃったね｡
This is bad! It's like the emergency bell went off inside him.
ﾆｷﾋﾞﾏﾝ言われても ｸﾚｰﾀｰ言われても
怒らなかった 浜田君が➡
Hamada didn't flinch when he was called "Crater-face,"
but that autumn during our second year in middle school,
ﾎﾞｺ言われたとたん ｲｽ放り投げて
暴れた 中学２年の秋！
he went crazy and threw chairs around when someone called him "Pock."
誰？ 浜田君って…｡
Who's Hamada?
You just said Odd Jobs, didn't you?
今… 万事屋って言ったな？
(じじい)つまり なに？
万事 何でもしてくれんの？
That means you'll do any kind of odd job for anyone?
何でもって 蘇生は無理ですから｡
I can't bring you back from the edge of the grave!
教会 行って ｺﾞｰﾙﾄﾞ払ってください｡
For that, please make a donation of gold at the church.
時々 ﾀﾀﾞで
やってくれるとこもあるけど➡
Sometimes, they'll do it for free. But Great-grandma told me not to say...
その場所は 教えちゃいけないって
ひいおばあちゃんが…｡
No, sorry. By gold, I'm talking about a game and...
ｳｿです… すみません！
ｺﾞｰﾙﾄﾞなんて ｹﾞｰﾑの話…
っていうか➡
Oh man, talking about a game in my final moments... Aghhh!
最後の話題が ｹﾞｰﾑﾈﾀなんて ｲﾔ～!!
♪♪～
Once again, Professor Jaijien will make his rounds.
(ｱﾅｳﾝｽ)再び じゃいじぇん教授の
総回診です｡
♪♪～
この かんざしの持ち主を
捜してほしいんじゃ｡
I want you to find the owner of this hair ornament.
それって どういう…｡
Why is that?
は つ こ いの人じゃ…｡
She was my first l-o-v-e.
ちょっと なに その酢こんぶ｡
Hey, what's with the pickled seaweed?
(神楽)聞くに堪えない話を
聞くときは➡
Whenever I hear a sad story, eating pickled seaweed calms my heart.
酢こんぶが 心の平衡を
保ってくれるね｡
この歳まで 所帯ももたんで➡
I've spent all my days chasing tail the whole time.
女のｹﾂばかり 追いかけてきたが…
なぜかな➡
But for some reason, all I can remember now is her smile.
今になって思い出すのは
あの人の笑顔ばかりでなぁ…｡
ｵﾚにも 酢こんぶくれ｡
Gimme some pickled seaweed, too.
２人ともかい！ 容赦ないな｡
Both of you? Pathetic!
笑ってくれて かまわんぞ｡
Laugh if you want.
こんな じじいが 死に際に
色気づきおって… とな…｡
An old man like me would yearn for love on his deathbed.
そんなことないですよ｡
I'm not laughing...
あれは 本当に
きれいな人じゃった…｡
She was so beautiful...
She always wore the kanzashi and worked hard every day.
(じじい)いつも かんざし挿して
ちゃきちゃき働く➡
巷でも評判の娘でのぅ｡
She was the talk of the town.
Ayano!
((男たち:綾乃さ～ん！))
Every man was in love with her.
(じじい)男どもは あの人目当てに
団子屋に通い詰め➡
And they all went to the shop where she worked and got fat eating dumplings.
みんな ﾌﾞｸﾌﾞｸに
肥え太っておったわ｡
ﾜｼも そうしたかったが
金もないし 何よりも ｳﾌﾞじゃった｡
I wanted to join them, but I had no money and besides, I was way too shy.
せいぜい 物陰から あの人の
働く姿 見るので 精一杯よ｡
All I could do was lurk behind corners to catch a glimpse of her.
(じじい)そんな ある日…｡
Then one day...
♪♪～
I see you've come to visit again.
((綾乃:また 来てらしたの？
あっ…！
Don't be shy! Come over here.
(綾乃)いいかげん
こっちにいらっしゃいな｡
(綾乃)いつも
そこから覗いてたの➡
You're always watching from over there.
ｱﾀｼ 知ってましたよ))
I see you every time.
♪♪～
(じじい)それが 彼女…➡
Those were the first words Ayano uttered to me.
綾乃さんと
初めて交わした言葉じゃった…｡
だが その直後…｡
But right after that...
You must really like it.
((綾乃:よっぽど 好きなのね｡
(咳き込む声)
はい どうぞ｡
えっ…？
Here you go.
食べたかったんでしょう？
You wanted these, didn't you?
But don't tell anyone, okay?
でも みんなには内緒ですよ))
(じじい)彼女は ﾜｼの思いには
気づいとらんかった…｡
She had no idea how I felt about her.
それは 幸いだったのかもしれん｡
Which was probably a stroke of luck.
なんせ 横にいるだけで
ﾜｼは 倒れそうだったから｡
After all, just being near her made me almost pass out.
当然 団子も のどを通らん｡
Of course, I couldn't even swallow the dumplings.
♪♪～
((あががが…！
ちょ… 大丈夫ですか!?
Are you all right?!
What's wrong?!
ちょっと… どうしたんですか!?))
(じじい)団子を
のどに詰まらせながら➡
As I lay there choking on the dumpling, I didn't think about dying.
ﾜｼの頭をしめたのは
己の生死よりも➡
My only thoughts were of regret that I wouldn't see her again.
こんな醜態を これ以上➡
彼女に見られたくないという
一念じゃった｡
((誰か来て～!! あっ…))
Somebody, help!
I pulled myself together and run away.
(じじい)ﾜｼは 気力を振りしぼって
逃げた…！
♪♪～
(じじい)気がついたときは
どこぞの路地で➡
When I regained my senses...
I was lying in some alley, covered in my own vomit.
へどまみれになって
倒れとったよ｡
((あっ…))
I had been half out of my mind when I ran,
(じじい)苦し紛れに
引き抜いてきてしまった➡
彼女のかんざしを握ってな…｡
and somehow I had grabbed her hair ornament on the way.
I want you to find her.
彼女を 捜してほしいんじゃ…｡
ｳﾁは 高いぜ｡
超一流の 万事屋だからな｡
It's gonna cost you. We're a top-class operation, after all.
(じじい)金ならある｡
I have money.
(じじい)ｷﾞｬﾙに いくら払っても
使い切れんくらいじゃ｡
I've spent all I want on women, and still I can't use it up.
(じじい)家族もおらんし
遺産をどうしようか➡
I have no family, so I've often wondered what to do about my wealth.
悩んどったくらいじゃ｡
ﾜｼの頼みを引き受けてくれれば
ｱﾝﾀたちに すべての遺産を残そう｡
If you accept my request, I'll leave you my entire fortune.
し… しかたねえなぁ｡
ん…？
Ah well, I guess we don't have much choice!
年寄りの頼みとあっちゃ
断るわけにもいかねえだろ｡
We can't turn down an old man's request.
って ｱﾝﾀ 笑いながら
怒る人みたいになってるよ！
You look like you're trying hard not to look so happy!
黙れ 新八！ お前は この依頼人の
お世話をするんだ!!
Shut up, Shinpachi!
You're gonna take good care of our client!
You put your heart and soul into this!
誠心誠意 真心を込めてな！
えぇ～？
ﾎﾞｸも 入院患者なんですけど…｡
Excuse me? I'm still a patient here.
ぶぁかやろ～！ 万事屋ってのは➡
You fool!
Odd Jobs exists to help people, right?!
人様のお役に立って なんぼだろ！
人生に 大事なのは
金でも学歴でもねえ！ 愛だ!!
It isn't money or education, but love. That's what's important in life!
And when a youth forgets vitality and kindness, then he's nothing.
気力と思いやりを忘れた若者は
これだから…｡
あれ…？ なんで ﾎﾞｸだけ
今どきの ﾀﾞﾒな若者にされてるの？
Huh? Why am I the hapless youth in this?
(神楽)遺産って 酢こんぶより
偉いｱﾙか？
Is "fortune" better than pickled seaweed?
酢こんぶﾌｧﾐﾘｰﾊﾟｯｸより 偉い｡
It's even better than a family pack of pickled seaweed.
(神楽)わ～お！
お～い!!
Wow!
Hey!
(店員)団子屋 ｢かんざし｣？
Kanzashi Dango Shop?
(店員)知らねえなぁ｡
Never heard of the place.
昔 この辺にあったって聞いたぜ｡
I heard it used to be in this district, a long time ago.
ﾀﾞﾒだ…｡ ｵﾗ ３日以上 前のことは
思い出せねえ｡
Nope, I can't remember anything beyond three days ago.
ﾆﾜﾄﾘ以下だな｡
You're worse than a chicken.
Since you're here... How about paying your bill, Gintoki?
それよりよ 銀時
お前 たまったﾂｹ 払ってけよ～！
最後に払ったのが 219日前だ｡
The last time you paid was 219 days ago.
それ以来 ﾂｹが
207日前の 磯辺団子｡
After that, you had isobe dumplings 207 days ago
202日前の
甘酒と きなこ餅に始まって…｡
and amazake and kinako dumplings 202 days ago...
And what?
なんだよ！
東海道線の 駅の名前➡
Are you like those kids who can memorize every stop on the Tokaido line from Tokyo?
東京から 全部 暗唱するｶﾞｷか
ｱﾝﾀは！
日が暮れちまうぞ～！
The day isn't long enough.
Anyway, we're looking for a girl named Ayano who used to work at this shop named Kanzashi.
それより その かんざしで
奉公してた➡
綾乃って娘を 捜してんだ｡
Well, it's over 50 years ago, so she's probably a granny now.
娘っても 50年も前だから
今は ばあさんだろうけどな…｡
Nope, no good. I'm not interested in chicks over forty years old.
ﾀﾞﾒだ～｡
ｵﾗ 40歳以上の女に興味ねえから｡
それより 銀時
お前 たまったﾂｹ 払ってけよ｡
Never mind that, Gintoki. Pay your tab, will you?
最後に払ったのが 219日前だ…｡
円周率 覚えたほうが➡
The last time you paid was 219 days ago.
You'd be more popular with chicks if you learn the formula for pi.
ﾓﾃるらしいぜ！
えっ!? ﾏｼﾞで!? あっ…！
Huh? For real?!
ちょっ…！ ｿ連の歴代書記長と
征夷大将軍 どっちが ｲｹてる～!?
Wait! Which is better?! Being able to name the chief secretaries of Russia or the shoguns?!
買ってきましたよ！
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣と ｢週ﾌﾟﾚ｣！
I bought it. Your JUMP and Weekly Playboy.
それと ｶﾖｺさんもﾘﾗさんも
電話番号が変わったか何かで➡
Also, I couldn't reach Kayoko and Rira because their phone numbers have been changed.
連絡つきませんでした｡
そうか…｡
I see.
じゃあ ﾏｲちゃんとｱﾕﾐちゃんに
電話してくれ｡
Then call Mai and Ayumi.
それと ﾌﾙｰﾂ牛乳と ｴﾋﾞｶﾂｻﾝﾄﾞを
買ってきてもらおうか｡
Then I want you to buy me some fruit-flavored milk and a fried shrimp sandwich.
えぇ～っ!?
ﾌﾙｰﾂ牛乳には➡
You've got to have fruit-flavored milk with a fried shrimp sandwich.
ｴﾋﾞｶﾂと決まっとるだろうが｡
そんなことも知らんのか｡
Don't you know even that?
No, I don't!
知らんっつうの！ ﾎﾞｸの周りには➡
Why do all the people around me have their own rules?!
ｵﾚﾙｰﾙの持ち主ばっかですか！
そんなことより…！
んっ？
Anyway...
ﾊﾟﾀｰﾝが いくつかあるな｡
I see three options.
１ 手相を見る｡ ２ 手を重ねる｡
1. Read your palm.
2. Hold hands.
３ ﾁｰを出す｡ さぁ どれ？
3. Paper.
Which is it?
Money! Pay up! Do you know how much I've spent on you so far?!
金だよ 金!! 金 払え!!
もう いくら立て替えてると
思ってんだ！
My goodness, you youngsters always thinking about money!
やれやれ…
昨今の若者は 金 金 金｡
嘆かわしい話だ｡ 金の亡者か！
How sad. Are you some money-cursing ghost?!
つきあいきれないよ｡
なんて じじいだ｡
I can't keep up with this! Who does he think he is, that old geezer?!
いちばん信じられないのは
あれだよ➡
And that's just unbelievable.
The photos in Playboy go from large to small.
週ﾌﾟﾚのｸﾞﾗﾋﾞｱは
大 中 小って揃ってんだよ｡
なんで 最初から
ちゃんと見ていかないんだよ｡
Why doesn't he look at them in order?! I can't believe he skipped pages!
ﾍﾟｰｼﾞ飛ばすなんて ありえないよ！
Oh, I can't stand that old pervert.
(看護師)もう ｲﾔんなっちゃうわ
あの ｴﾛじじい｡
脳みそ
かち割ってやればいいのよ！
Just shake that head of his.
いくら 白衣の天使だって
殺意くらい湧くわよ｡
They may call us angels in white, but it's enough to make me wanna kill.
ﾁｯﾌﾟもらえるなら ともかくさ｡
無理無理｡
It'd be a different story if we got tips for this.
Not gonna happen.
入院費だって
もう何か月 滞納してるか｡
Even his hospital bills have piled up for months. He's famous for being broke.
お金ないの 有名だもん｡
あの ｴﾛじじい…！
Why that old pervert.
(２人)あの くそｴﾛじじい!!
Why that dirty, old bastard!
♪♪～
(２人)金～っ!!
Money!
Oh, you found out?
あ ﾊﾞﾚた？
(神楽/銀時)だぁ～っ！
よ～ く～ も～!!
How dare you?!
待て待て 待て｡
お前は 金ごときで➡
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Are you trying to ruin an old man's dream all because of a little thing like money?
老人の 生きる希望を
奪い去ろうとするのか…｡
How dare you say such a thing!
どの口で そんなことを言うｱﾙか！
ｲﾃﾃﾃﾃ…！
金の切れ目が 縁の切れ目ってな｡
When the money runs dry, so does our relationship. It's over.
降ろさせてもらうぜ｡
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟは もらっていきます｡
10週目が 気になりますから｡
I'm taking the JUMP. I wanna know what happens in the tenth issue.
病院食もね｡
薄甘いﾃﾞｻﾞｰﾄが 気になるね｡
This hospital food, too. I'm sorta curious about the lightly sweetened desserts.
というわけだ｡ 悪く思うなよ｡
So that's it. No hard feelings eh?
(じじい)ううっ…｡
(じじい)これで ﾜｼが
ただの ｴﾛじじいではなく➡
So now you know, I'm not just some old pervert...
病弱な ｴﾛじじいであることが
わかってもらえたじゃろう｡
...I'm a very sick old pervert.
ﾚｲｶちゃんは この こけた頬が
たまらんと言うての…｡
Reika says my hollow cheeks are irresistible.
憂いに沈む様子が
そそるわと言ったのは➡
Who was it that said something about being oppressed with sorrow?
誰じゃったか…｡
Oh yes, that was Kana.
そうそう ｶﾅちゃんじゃ｡
その顔色 ｱﾝﾀ 本当は…｡
Your pallor... Are you really?
あの団子事件には
続きがあるんだ｡ 聞くか？
There's more to the dumpling story. Will you listen?
(じじい)あのあと
人づてに聞いた話によると➡
Later, I heard that she got fired from the shop.
彼女は あの店を
辞めさせられちまったらしい｡
(じじい)ﾜｼだけじゃない｡
It wasn't just me.
貧しい子供や 腹ぺこの野良犬や
野良猫を見つけては➡
She secretly gave dumplings to poor kids, hungry stray dogs and cats,
内緒で 団子を食べさせてたんだ｡
as she came across them.
ﾜｼの一件で 主人に
それが露見しちまって➡
Her boss found out that she'd given me free dumplings.
辞めさせられちまったのさ…｡
So I was the reason she was fired.
本当に 悪いことしちまった…｡
I did a terrible thing. Now it's too late to apologize.
今さら謝っても
詮ないことだが…｡
死ぬ前に せめて
あの かんざしだけでも➡
I wanted to at least return her hair ornament before I died.
返したくてのぅ…｡
Actually, I'd just like to see her smiling face one more time.
いや… ﾎﾝﾄのこと言うと➡
また あの笑顔を
見たいだけなんだけどな…｡
あっ…｡
行くぞ｡
Let's go.
帰るんですか？
かんざしの持ち主捜し 続行だ！
We're leaving?
We're going to find the owner of the hair ornament.
(新八/神楽)えぇ～っ!?
Huh?
いいか！
昼間に いちご牛乳を飲みすぎて➡
Listen.
Let's say you drink too much strawberry milk during the day
夜中に ﾄｲﾚに
行きたくなったとしよう｡
and wake up in the middle of the night to go to the bathroom.
しかし 布団の外は寒い｡
布団から 出たくない｡
But it's cold outside. You don't want to leave the comfort of your futon.
しかし 尿意は強まる一方だ！
But the urge to pee gets stronger and stronger!
懊悩 煩悶 葛藤！
一大決心をして ﾄｲﾚに行く!!
Anguish! Worry! Trouble!
You make up your mind and go to the toilet!
便器の前に立つ！ 取り出す！
発射！ この開放感!!
You stand in front of the john! You let loose!
Man, that feeling of release!
このために
生きてきたとさえ思える瞬間だ！
All that pent-up feeling being released!
だが そこで気づく！
But then you realize... you're not in front of the john, you're still under the covers!
ｵﾚがいるのは ﾄｲﾚじゃない｡
布団の中だ！
太ももに広がる
生あたたかい感触！
That warm feeling spreads between your thighs. But it won't stop. You can't stop!
だが 止まらない｡
止められな～い！
That's what it's all about.
そういうもんなんだよ 何事も！
それが 真の
いちごぎゅうにゃーなんだ！
That's the true nature of Strawberry Milky! Understand?!
わかったか!!
いちごぎゅうにゃー!!
Strawberry Milky!
つうか…｡
(人々)いちごぎゅうにゃー！
That's it...
Strawberry Milky!
(神楽たち)いちごぎゅうにゃー!!
Strawberry Milky! Strawberry Milky!
Strawberry Milky!
(みんな)いちごぎゅうにゃー!!
Strawberry Milky! Strawberry Milky!
(猫の鳴き声)
つっても こんな
どこにでもある かんざし➡
But how are we gonna track down the owner of a common hair ornament?
どうやって
調べればいいんだか…｡
いいｱｲﾃﾞｱがあるね｡
I have an idea.
(神楽)見つけたら かじり放題ね
定春｡
Sadaharu, if you find her, you can chew this up all you like.
お～い！ さすがに 無理でしょ!!
Hey, that's ridiculous!
つか かじり放題って なに!?
誰を!?
What do you mean "chew this up all you like"?! Who is "this"?
ﾆﾔﾘ｡
ﾆﾔﾘじゃねえつうの～!!
Smile.
What kind of smile is that?!
50年も経ってるんだ｡
It's been fifty years! There's no scent left on it.
においなんて
残ってるわけないって｡
わからないｱﾙよ｡
綾乃さん もしかして➡
Who knows? Maybe Ayano had strong B.O.?
体臭 きつかったかもしれないｱﾙ｡
えぇ～？ 体臭って…｡
青少年の 甘酸っぱい夢を➡
What?! Body odor?
Don't shatter my youthful dreams of a woman, pickled seaweed girl!
さらっと打ち砕くな
この 酢こんぶ娘！
いやいや 安心したまえ 新八君｡
Don't worry, Shinpachi. Pretty girls always smell good, no exception.
べっぴんさんってのは 大抵
理屈抜きで➡
いいにおいが するもんですよ｡
いや… でも べっぴんのくせに➡
Although, there are some who are pretty but have strong body odor.
体臭きついってのも…｡
ﾏﾆｱ…？
Is that a fetish?
いやいや いや～｡
完璧な女より 逆に なんかこう➡
No, no, no... Rather than the perfect woman, it makes you remember her, you know?
燃えるっつうか そそるものが…
ん…？
Huh?! Hey! You led us back home!
って おい!! お前 家に
戻ってきてんじゃねえか！
散歩気分で ｼｬﾗﾝﾗ ﾍｲか｡ ﾊﾞｶ野郎！
Did you think you were just out for a walk, moron?!
(定春)ﾊｯ ﾊｯ ﾊｯ…｡
What is it? You're supposed to pee outside! Life is all about hit-and-run!
なんだよ～？ ﾄｲﾚは
外で しろっつってんだろうが！
人生 ﾋｯﾄ ｴﾝﾄﾞ ﾗﾝなんだよ！
(定春)ﾊｯ ﾊｯ ﾊｯ…｡
おい まさか…｡
まさかね…｡
Hey, you don't think?
No way...
ﾊｯ ﾊｯ ﾊｯ…｡
Whatcha want?
(お登勢)なんだよ…
家賃 払いにきたのかい？
Came to pay the rent?
お前ら こちとら
夜の蝶だからよぅ➡
Listen, I'm a creature of the night, so I don't work during the day.
昼間は
活動 停止してるっつったろ｡
来るなら 夜来い ﾎﾞｹ！
Come back when it's dark, idiot!
いやいや～ これは ないよな…｡
No, there's no way she's...
(２人)ないない！
Nope, not way.
綾乃って面じゃねえもんな｡
She doesn't look like an Ayano.
(２人)ないない！
Nope, no way.
なんで ｱﾀｼの本名 知ってんだい？
How do you know my real name?
Wha?!
頭が痛い～!!
My head is gonna explode! I can't understand her words?!
理解できない言葉が～!!
ｳｿつくんじゃねえ ﾊﾞﾊﾞｱ!!
Don't mess with me, granny!
No way are you Ayano!
ｵﾒｴが 綾乃のわけねえだろ！
If that's your name, then "battleship" would come before it!
100歩 譲っても
上に ｢宇宙戦艦｣がつくよ～！
おい～!! ﾒｶ扱いか～!!
Heey!! You callin' me a battle axe?!
お登勢ってのは 源氏名…
いわば 夜の名前よ｡
Otose is an alias. My professional name.
本名は 寺田 綾乃っていうんだ｡
My real name is Ayano Terada.
ｱﾘﾝｺさん お散歩 楽しいですか？
Little ants, out for a nice walk?
(お登勢)なに わかりやすい
現実逃避してんだ！
You can't cover up the truth with inane babble! I am Ayano, not an ant!
ｱﾘより 綾乃だろうが！
[TEL]
はい ｽﾅｯｸ お登勢｡
Yes? Otose Snack Shop.
えっ？ 万事屋？
What? Odd Jobs?
大江戸病院から 電話だよ｡
It's a call for you from Oedo Hospital.
なんか じいさんが
もうやばいとか言ってるけど｡
Something about an old man in critical condition.
知り合いが 入院してんのかい？
Someone you know in the hospital?
(じゃいじぇん)
非常に 危険な状態だ｡
His condition is critical. He's nearing his end.
そろそろかもしれないね｡
(婦長)心臓に 治療不可能な病気を
抱えていましたからね｡
He had an untreatable heart condition.
(じゃいじぇん)
しかし あれだな…｡
Well... I understand he was quite the lady's man,
女遊びの激しい人だと
聞いていたが➡
誰一人 看取りにきてくれんとは
寂しいもんだな…｡
but not a single one of them has come to his bedside. How sad.
まぁ 病院としちゃ➡
In any case, as far as the hospital is concerned, we'll have one less problematic patient.
問題患者がいなくなってくれれば
助かるけどね｡
じゃいじぇん先生
脈が弱まってきました｡
Dr. Jaijien, his pulse is weakening.
Look out! It's a runaway horse!
(男)暴れ馬だ～！
(女)ｷｬ～ｯ！ 助けて～!!
Help!
(町娘)ｷｬｯ！
(町人)あぶねえ！
Watch out!
♪♪～
あぁ～～っ!!
ﾁｯｷｼｮｳ～!!
Damn it!
さっき 何か踏みましたよ！
Hey, we stepped on something just now!
気にすることないね｡
Forget it.
In the pursuit of our mission, a few small sacrifices are nothing!
ｵﾚたちの 崇高な人助けの前に
小さな犠牲は つきものさ！
あれ 人でしたよ！
確かに 人！ たぶん 人!!
That was a person! Maybe a person. It was a person!
違うな｡
どっちかっていうと➡
Nah.
I think it was a pebble or a cottonball.
石ころとか 綿ぼこりの仲間ｱﾙね｡
ひどいね おい…｡
You guys are awful.
(じゃいじぇん)いよいよか｡
It's time.
No one came to his deathbed, after all.
結局 誰も
最期 間に合いませんでしたね｡
(２人)だぁ～っ!!
Old man!
じいさん!!
Wh-Who are you people?!
なんだ!? ｷﾐたちは！
いちごぎゅうにゃーどうしの
約束だ！
Strawberry Milky has a promise to keep to a comrade.
連れてきてやったぞ｡
I brought her to you.
じゃ… じゃいじぇん先生
意識が…！
D-Dr. Jaijien! He's conscious!
なにっ!?
What?!
おい 聞いてんのか？ じいさん｡
Hey, are you listening?
ちょっと ｷﾐ 何やってんの～!!
Hey, what are you doing?!
(じゃいじぇん)し… 白い巨獣…｡
A-A giant white beast!
(婦長)先生!!
Doctor!
I returned the kanzashi. Can you see, old man?
かんざしは
きっちり 返したからな｡
見えるか？ じいさん｡
《あぁ… 見えるともさ…》
Yes, I can see.
♪♪～
綾乃さん…｡
Ayano...
♪♪～
ｱﾝﾀ… やっぱり かんざし…➡
You look great with that kanzashi.
よく 似合うなぁ…｡
♪♪～
((ありがとう｡ 返してくれて｡
Thank you for returning it.
ｴｯﾍﾍﾍ))
♪♪～
やれやれ…｡ いきなり どこに
連れていかれるかと思ったら…｡
Oh dear, I wondered where you were taking me.
でも いい顔してましたね｡
ふ～ん｡
But...he looked happy.
ばあさんよ…｡
Hey, granny?
あ～ん？
ｱﾝﾀ ひょっとして…➡
Did you actually remember him?
覚えてたってことはねえよな？
Remember what?
何をだい？
いや つまり…｡
I mean...
(お登勢)さぁね｡
I wonder...
(お登勢)さてと…｡
And now...
団子でも 食べにいくとするかい？
...why don't we go have some dumplings?
あ… あぁ…｡
Y-Yeah.
♪♪～
[Mini 3-Z Ginpachi Sensei]
Mini...
Ginpachi Sensei!
Listen up, everyone.
This kanji is tou [sugar]. It's written this way
the characters hito, hito, hito [man, man, man] are supporting each other carrying the cross and going to the land of Tou.
It's an ancient, ancient story.
Sensei, why are you talking ancient history?
いいか お前ら｡
｢糖｣という字はなぁ…➡
人と 人と
人と 人が支え合って➡
十字架 担いで
唐の国に行きましたとさ｡
むか～しむかしの話じゃった｡
(女子生徒)先生
昔話になってます｡
[Preview]
A cat-eared character debuts!
What? Are our ratings so bad that we need blatant moe pandering?
And don't tell me...you're that cute character?
The next episode:
"People Who Make Good First Impressions Usually Suck"
[This is a snack house, a place for old men to drink themselves sick and indulge their sick minds.]
[Mu, a regular customer of "Otose"]
Is working for a big advertisement agency.
Battleship Ayano!
宇宙戦艦 綾乃～!!